Guide to the Yale Tocqueville Manuscripts
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- AMERICAN TRIP, APRIL 1831--APRIL 1832; B.
  - Letters and Reports, 1
    - B.I.c. Correspondence and Relations with Americans, 1831-32: - (Letters, diaries, essays, etc.) (Box 6)
      - [mars 1831] Ch. Lucas to Tocqueville with letters of introduction. (not now on hand) (Original from Larminat: noted also by GWP)
      -18 Feb. 1832, (N.Y.), Gustave de Beaumont to Edward Everett (GWP copy from MHS: Everett)
      -18 Feb. 1832, N.Y., R. Riker to Tocqueville and Beaumont (Doysie copy from Redier MSS; see White Cat. 3W: Dossier I. 24)
      -19 Feb. 1832, N.Y., R. Riker to Tocqueville and Beaumont (Doysie copy from Redier MSS; see White Cat. 3W: Dossier I. 11)
      -19 Feb. 1832, N.Y., Robert Emmet, to Tocqueville (Doysie copy from Redier MSS; see White Cat. 3W: Dossier I. 10)
      -19 Feb. (1832) (N.Y.), Jared Sparks diary note (GWP copy from H: Sparks)
      -(Feb. 1832), ( Phila.), William Short note to Neuville (GWP copy from LC: Short)
      -(Feb. 1832), Boston, Joseph Coolidge Jr., answers (Doysie copy from Redier MSS; see White Cat. 3W: Dossier I. 17)
      -1... Feb. 1832 ("1831"), (N.Y.), Tocqueville to Poinsett (Bonnel copy from Tocqueville Tocqueville brouillon)
      -Th. L. McKenney to Gustave de Beaumont (Doysie copy from Redier MSS; see White Cat. 3W: Dossier II. 33g8)
      -5 March 1832, Boston, Francis Lieber to ? (Original from Larminat: GWP noted from Beaumont-la-Chartre)
      -13 April 1832, Phila., B.W. Richards to Gustave de Beaumont (Noted by GWP from Beaumont-la-Chartre)
      -1 mai 1832, Paris, Beaumont to Edward Everett (GWP copy from MHS: Everett)
      -25 June 1832, Robert Walsh to Tocqueville and Beaumont (Original from Larminat: GWP noted from Beaumont-la-Chartre)
      -8 Oct. 1832, Phila., Dannery to Gustave de Beaumont (Original from Larminat: GWP noted from Beaumont-la-Chartre)
      -15 Oct. 1832, Washington, Serurier to Gustave de Beaumont (Original from Larminat: GWP noted from Beaumont-la-Chartre)
      -Beaumont Article on Lieber Encyclop. (Brouillon - GWP note from Beaumont-la-Chartre For Original see C.I.d.)
      -16 9bre, 1832, Paris, Beaumont to Lieber (Photocopy from Hunt: See B.IV.c.)
      -19 Nov. 1832, New York, Francis Lieber to Beaumont and Tocqueville (GWP noted from Beaumont-la-Chartre Original from Larminat. See C.I.a.)
      -18 Dec. 1832, Paris, Tocqueville to Jared Sparks (GWP copy from H: Sparks)
      -7 Jan. 1833, New York, Francis Lieber to Gustave de Beaumont (GWP noted from Beaumont-la-Chartre Original from Larminat. See C.I.a.)
      -23 Jan. (1833), New York, Francis Lieber to Gustave de Beaumont (GWP noted from Beaumont-la-Chartre: Original from Larminat. See C.I.a.)
      -5 mars 1833, Paris, D.D. Warden to Beaumont and Tocqueville (Original from Larminat)
      (Last ten items - excluding the last one - are also listed under C.I.d.)
      See also C.I.d; D.II; E.IV.: Lieber Photostats, Great Lakes Photostats, and Neilson Photostats in B.IV.
    - B.I.d. Letters from French Friends, 1831-32 (Box 6)
      -4 mai 1831, Ernest de Chabrol to Tocqueville (Bonnel copy from Tocqueville Tocqueville MSS)
      -10 juin 1831, Metz, Eugene Stoffels to Tocqueville (Bonnel copy from Tocqueville Tocqueville MSS)
      -25 juillet, 1831, Paris, unidentified [perhaps Elie de Beaumont--Jardin] to Tocqueville (Bonnel copy from Tocqueville Tocqueville MSS)
      -16 aout (1831), Felix Le Peletier d'Aunay to Tocqueville (Bonnel copy from Tocqueville Tocqueville MSS)
      -aout 1831, Paris, Felix Le Peletier d'Aunay to Gustave de Beaumont (Bonnel copy from Tocqueville Tocqueville MSS)
      -25 Nov. (1831), Versailles, Felix Le Peletier d'Aunay [?] to Tocqueville (GWP note from Tocqueville Tocqueville MSS)
      -13 Xbre 1831, Metz, Eugene Stoffels to Tocqueville (Bonnel copy from Tocqueville Tocqueville MSS)
      -25 Xbre 1831, F. Carne to Tocqueville (GWP note from Tocqueville Tocqueville MSS)
      -19 Oct. 1832, Mareil, Felix Le Peletier d'Aunay to Gustave de Beaumont (GWP copy from Beaumont-la-Chartre letterbook. For original see B.I.e.)
      -1 Nov. 1832, Mareil, Felix Le Peletier d'Aunay to Gustave de Beaumont (GWP copy from Beaumont-la-Chartre letterbook. For original see B.I.e.)
      See also GWP notes (E.IV. a, b.) and C.III: Help from others.
    - B.I.e. Tocqueville and Beaumont relations with French Government: Letters concerning their Prison Mission. (Box 6)
      Original manuscripts acquired at various times from Mme de Larminat. GWP had previously made some notes on certain of these documents at Beaumont-la-Chartre.
      -27 9bre 1830, Paris, copy of letter from Minister of Interior to Gustave de Beaumont (Larminat)
      -25 novembre 1830, Paris, Conseiller Ch. Renouard to Gustave de Beaumont (Larminat)
      -27 novembre 1830, Paris, Montalivet to Gustave de Beaumont (Larminat)
      -24 janvier 1831, Felix Le Peletier d'Aunay to Gustave de Beaumont (Larminat)
      -draft of letter to Garde des Sceaux requesting continuance of Beaumont's salary (Larminat)
      -27 janvier 1831, Paris, Merilhou [?] to Tocqueville (Larminat)
      -27 janvier 1831, Paris, Merilhou [?] to Gustave de Beaumont (Larminat)
      -31 jan. [1831?], Prefet of Police, to M. Didier on Tocqueville and Beaumont leave. (Larminat)
      -fevrier 1831, Paris, Merilhou [?] to Gustave de Beaumont (Larminat)
      -7 fevrier 1831, Paris, Didier to Beaumont and Tocqueville (Larminat)
      -27 fevr. 1831, Procureur General to Gustave de Beaumont (Larminat)
      -28 mars 1831, Paris, Edmond Blanc to ? (Larminat)
      -24 mars 1831, Ministere de la Marine et des Colonies to Tocqueville (Larminat)
      -mars 1831, Inspector General of Prisons, Ch. Lucas to Tocqueville and Beaumont on prison questions. (Larminat)
      -2 Sept. 1831, Paris, Barthe [?] to Gustave de Beaumont urging return (Larminat)
      -7 Sept. 1831, Minister of Commerce to Tocqueville and Beaumont, Questions and Answers. (and GWP note) (Larminat)
      -dimanche, unidentified to Gustave de Beaumont (Larminat)
      -12 avril 1832, Paris, Beaumont to Secretaire general, draft of letter sent 3 May. (Larminat)
      -10 mai 1832, Paris, Edmond Blanc to Gustave de Beaumont (Larminat)
      -12 juillet 1832, draft of protest to Prefect because not allowed to visit Paris prisons (Larminat)
      -19 oct. 1832, Felix Le Peletier d'Aunay to Gustave de Beaumont (Larminat)
      -1 nov. 1832, Felix Le Peletier d'Aunay to Gustave de Beaumont (Larminat)
      -26 novembre 1832, Paris, Edmond Blanc to Beaumont and Tocqueville (Larminat)
      -15 dec. 1832, Garde des Sceaux to Beaumont and Tocqueville (Larminat)
      -24 dec. 1832, Salvandy to Gustave de Beaumont (Larminat)
      -28 jan. 1833, Broglie, Minister of Foreign Affairs to Tocqueville and Beaumont (Larminat)
      -25 mars 1833, Inspector General of Prisons to Gustave de Beaumont (Larminat)
      -1 avril 1833, unidentified to Gustave de Beaumont (Larminat)
      -20 novembre 1833, extract of article in Le Blaisois criticizing their mission, with draft of a reply. (Larminat)
    - B.I.f. Materials on American Penitentiaries:
      [MS Vault Microfilm 640, reel 1, neg mf]
      1. Tocqueville and Beaumont Periodical Reports to the Government on the Progress of their Mission. 1831-32:
      -7 juin 1831, Sing Sing, Tocqueville to Felix Le Peletier d'Aunay (draft) (GWP note from Beaumont-la-Chartre; For original see B.I.f.2)
      -juin 1831, Report to Ministry of Interior on Sing Sing and House of Refuge, with ?s. (draft by Beaumont, 14 pages) (GWP note from Beaumont-la-Chartre)
      -juin 1831, Report to Garde des Sceaux on Sing Sing and House of Refuge (Beaumont, 40 plus pages, notes and draft) (GWP note from Beaumont-la-Chartre)
      -juin 1831, Report on Blackwell, Bellevue, Bridwell (in Beaumont's hand, never sent) (GWP note from Beaumont-la-Chartre)
      -27 juin 1831, Report [?] on House of Refuge, N.Y. (in Beaumont's hand, 30 pages draft) (GWP note from Beaumont-la-Chartre)
      -1831, Report on Auburn and Sing Sing to Ministry of Interior. (in Tocqueville's hand, 12 pages draft) (GWP note from Beaumont-la-Chartre; For original see B.I.f.2)
      -2 7bre 1831, Report to Garde des Sceaux on Penitentiary System and Penal Laws. (GWP note from Beaumont-la-Chartre)
      -6 8bre 1831, Report and questions to Procureur General (in Beaumont's hand, 20 pages draft) (GWP note from Beaumont-la-Chartre For original see B.I.f.2)
      -10 9bre 1831, Report to Minister of Interior Mole on Boston and Wethersfield (in Beaumont's hand, 17 pages draft) (GWP note from Beaumont-la-Chartre)
      -Letters to Ministere des Travaux Publics et du Commerce (in Beaumont's hand, few pages draft) (GWP note from Beaumont-la-Chartre)
      -10 Nov 1831, Report to Minister of Interior on Pennsylvania Penitentiary System (in Tocqueville's hand, 20 pages) (GWP note from Beaumont-la-Chartre)
      2. Penitentiary Notes and Reports from America in Tocqueville's hand: (from Larminat)
      /1/ Projet de lettre ecrite de Philadelphie le 10 9bre 1831 sur le systeme penitentiaire adopte en Pennsylvanie, adressee au Ministre de l'Interieur. 20 folio pages.
      /2/ Rapport sur "La Societe de discipline des prisons". 114 pages folio et 4to.
      /3/ Notes diverses sur les prisons des Etats-Unis, les ecoles de prisonniers, les statistiques, les moyennes des detenus dans les differents Etats. 90 pages folio et 4to.
      /4/ Rapport sur la prison de Sing-Sing, sous forme de projet de lettre, envoyee d'Auburn le 14 juillet 1831, adressee au Ministre de l'Interieur. 12 folio pages.
      /5/ Notes sur les penitenciers de Richemont, Baltimore, etc. Nombreuses notes statistiques. 27 folio pages.
      /6/ Rapport sur l'Etat de Maryland. 12 folio pages.
      /7/ Rapport sur l'Etat de Connecticut. 14 folio pages.
      /8/ Rapport sur l'Etat de Massachusetts. 10 folio pages.
      /9/ Rapport sur Philadelphie. 17 pages folio et 4to. including 2 pages later notes.
      /10/ Rapport sur l'Etat de New-York. 24 pages folio et 4to.
      /11/ Rapport sur l'Etat de Pennsylvanie. 21 pages folio et 4to.
      /12/ Tableaux des individus entres dans les prisons de Newgate et de Sing-Sing, classes par nature de delits. 19 pages 4to.
      /13/ Projet de lettre a son cousin Felix Le Peletier d'Aunay, sur le systeme penitentiaire, ecrit a Sing-Sing, le 7 juin, 1831. 12 pages 4to.
      /14/ Extrait du rapport de la "Society and house of refuge for the reformation of Juvenil delinquants." 3 folio pages.
      /15/ Notes sur les prisons des Etats-Unis, classees par ordre alphabetique. 13 pages 4to.
      /16/ Carnet de notes sur les prisonniers, en partie inedit, de 32 pages, dont 17 de la main de Gustave de Beaumont, 12mo, contenant des interviews de tres nombreux prisonniers americains. Some of Tocqueville's written over in ink.
      3. Notes and Manuscript in Tocqueville's hand for Du Systeme Penitentiaire aux Etats-Unis. (Originals from Larminat)
      /1/ Notes sur les chatiments corporels. 5 pages 4to.
      /2/ Notes sur les colonies agricoles. 17 pages 4to.
      /3/ Le pauperisme en Amerique. 4 pages 4to.
      /4/ Emprisonnement pour dettes. 2 pages 4to.
      /5/ Notes sur les prisons. 10 pages in. 4 dont 5 pages de la main de Gustave de Beaumont.
      /6/ Notes statistiques sur les differents Etats. 39 pages 4to.
      /7/ Statistiques sur les femmes et sur les negres en prison, etc. 29 pages in.
      /8/ Notes comparatives sur les differents Etats. 18 pages 4to.
      /9/ Tableau des criminels par rapport a la population. 5 pages 4to.
      /10/ Tableau statistique. 20 pages 4to.
      /11/ Notes diverses c. 20 pages including opinion of Mr. Smith.
      4. Notes and Manuscripts for second edition [?] of Du systeme penitentiaire [?] (Originals from Larminat)
      /1/ Draft of letter by Gustave de Beaumont submitting report to Secretary of State for Public Works and Commerce.
      -Gustave de Beaumont: "Historique du Systeme Penitentiaire"
      -Gustave de Beaumont: Maisons de refuge.
      -Gustave de Beaumont: Discipline (Auburn)
      5. Undated Fragments. (Originals from Larminat)
      -Gustave de Beaumont: 7 aout Prison de la Roquette
      -Tocqueville note on penitentiary of Geneva [?].
      -Scraps and notes in Tocqueville's hand: prison statistics, etc. (Larminat)
      6. Miscellaneous Beaumont Prison Materials. (Originals from Larminat)
      -Projet de Prison Centrale and law of 9 avril 1819 with La Rochefoucauld quote.
      -manuscript bibliographic lists for central penitentiary systems of New Jersey, Pennsylvania, Massachusetts, Connecticut; for hospitals, etc.; for manuscript docts en penit. system and judiciary (including manuscripts from McIlvaine, Welles, Judge McLean)
      -bibliography in six packages as turned over to the French Government by Beaumont and Tocqueville, including general works, houses of refuge, Newgate, Auburn, Maryland, commerce and public works.
      -notes and translation of parts of Boston Prison Discipline. See report 2 jan. 26.
      -unfinished manuscript by Beaumont - some kind of prison report, 55 pages both sides with first seven missing.
      -draft report by Beaumont to Garde des Sceaux on Maisons de Refuge, 20 pages
      -draft report to Ministry of Interior 10 Nov. 1831 on prisons of Boston and Wethersfield.
      -report (not sent) on Blackwell's I., Bridwell, Bellevue.
      -draft June 1831 on Sing Sing and N.Y. House of Refuge, to Ministry of Interior.
      -Westchester Herald 26 April 1831 marked: Antidote to Boston Prison Discipline Society Report.
      -manuscript notes from Robt. Wiltse and of Recorder Riker's views 22 May 1831.
      -notes from annual prison reports.
      -plan and manuscript ground plan of Sing Sing prison and grounds.
      -draft of letter to Pres. [?] Genl. 6 8bre 1831.
      -translation of brochure on rules and regulations.
      -miscellaneous notes on Philadelphia prisons and House of Refuge.
      -notes and questions on N.Y. House of Refuge, with some answers of Mr. Hart.
      -notes on Auburn, Boston, Wethersfield.
      -draft of letter to be sent to State Attorneys General.
      -note on Liverpool statistics.
      -pencil note on Bellevue, Bridwell.
      -requisitions and work reports of N.C. Hart.
      -Drafts of questions on penal codes and penitentiary systems, including several versions corrected in pencil in other hands or expanded to cover particular areas such as New Hampshire. One such document served as a model of a letter to be sent to the American prison wardens whom Tocqueville and Beaumont were not able to visit. (Larminat)
      -Copy of a letter that we intend to direct to the General Attorneys of some States (a modification of previous drafts with inserted corrections). (Larminat)
      -Some questions on crime in Massachusetts (in pencil) (Larminat)
      -Lithograph of Eastern State Penitentiary at Cherry Hill (Larminat)
      -Beaumont note on emprisonment absolu (Larminat)
      -Empris[onnement]t solitaire Auburn (in Beaumont's hand) (Larminat)
      -Plan of a new prison invented by Col. William Powers... Auburn. (Larminat)
      -Note on costs in smith and machine shop (with Tocqueville note giving source) (Larminat)
      -Longhand copy of article in Times of London of 31 Dec. 1831, reporting on progress of their prison mission. (Larminat)
      -Two questionnaires on American prisons and prison reforms, each apparently a fair copy by some American copyist, presumably in Philadelphia. Both in English. The one-page questionnaire has no date or signatures. The four-page questionnaire is signed individually by Gustave de Beaumont and Alexis de Tocqueville, and is dated in Beaumont's hand: Philadelphia, the 19th November 1831. There is also a postscript in Beaumont's hand requesting that the answers be sent in care of the French Minister Serurier in Washington. (Larminat to GWP)
      - 1. Tocqueville and Beaumont Periodical Reports to the Government on the Progress of their Mission. 1831-32. (Box 7)
        -10 Nov 1831, Report to Minister of Interior on Pennsylvania Penitentiary System (in Tocqueville's hand, 20 pages)
      - 2. Penitentiary Notes and Reports from America in Tocqueville's hand: (from Larminat) (Box 7)
      - 3. Notes and Manuscript in Tocqueville's hand for Du Systeme Penitentiaire aux Etats-Unis. (Originals from Larminat) (Box 7)
      - 4. Notes and Manuscripts for second edition [?] of Du systeme penitentiaire [?] (Originals from Larminat) (Box 7)
      - 5. Undated Fragments. (Originals from Larminat) (Box 7)
      - 6. Miscellaneous Beaumont Prison Materials. (Originals from Larminat) (Box 8)
  - American Trip Diaries & Notes, 1831-1832; 2
    - a. Tocqueville Travel Diaries: (Copies by Bonnel from Tocqueville Tocqueville MSS) (Box 9)
      -Cahiers Portatifs: 1-2-3-4-5: Itinerary and some conversations. (Cahiers 1-2-3 copied from Tocqueville Tocqueville MSS, Paquet 18; Cahiers 4-5 copied separately in 1930)
      -Cahiers Non-Alphabetiques: 1-2-3: Conversations. (Copied from Tocqueville Tocqueville MSS, Paquet 19. v. 1 and 2)
      -Cahiers Alphabetiques: A and B: Reflections, etc. (Copied from Tocqueville Tocqueville MSS, Paquet 19. v. 2 and 3)
      -Petit Cahier A: Canada. (Copied separately in 1930)
      -Petit Cahier: Notes sur Kent's Commentaries (Copied separately in 1930)
      -Cahier E: General notes and Conversations. (Doysie copy from Redier MSS; see White Cat. 3W: Dossier II. 33f)
      -Cahier F: Droit civil et criminal en Amerique (Doysie copy from Redier MSS; see White Cat. 3W: Dossier I. 23)
    - b. Tocqueville General Notes: (Box 10)
      For Chronological use, see GWP Outline Roll: (E.IV.C.6) The pencil numbers in margin of diary copies were inserted by GWP for ready reference from this Outline Roll.
      -Dates de mon voyage d'Amerique (Bonnel copy from Tocqueville Tocqueville MSS)
      -Notes diverses employees par Beaumont pour son edition (Bonnel copy from Tocqueville Tocqueville MSS, Paquet 17: 3 copies, of which 1 sent to Tocqueville Archives)
      -Shipboard conversations on national character, etc. (Doysie copy from Redier MSS; see White Cat. 3W: Dossier I. 20-1)
      -La seule verite... (Copied by Bonnel from Tocqueville Tocqueville MSS 1930)
      -long list of questions on many topics for organization of book. (Doysie copy from Redier MSS; see White Cat. 3W: Dossier I. 25)
      -Justice criminelle: list of 42 questions: 18 on criminal justice, the rest are general. (Doysie copy from Redier MSS; see White Cat. 3W: Dossier I. 15)
      -Instruction publique - lists of questions: 6 on education, 6 on government, 11 on common law, 3 on roads, plus miscellaneous. (Doysie copy from Redier MSS; see White Cat. 3W: Dossier I. 3-4-5)
      -Matieres politiques: jurisdiction of courts (Doysie copy from Redier MSS; see White Cat. 3W: Dossier II. 33g)
    - c. Beaumont Notes: (Box 10)
      -6 June 1831, Certificate on Tocqueville's new politeness. (Bonnel copy from Tocqueville Tocqueville MSS)
      -29 7bre 1831, Sparks conversation; Conversation with Sears, 19 7bre 1831; Note on D. Webster, 18 7bre 1831. (Original from Larminat: GWP copy from Beaumont-la-Chartre)
      -26-28 oct. 1831, Conversations and notes on Canada (Original from Larminat)
      -"Dernier chapitre. Note sur le Canada" (Original from Larminat)
      -Names of Americans (to see, or seen).
  - American Sketches, 3
    - a. Verbal sketches - all by Tocqueville (Box 11)
      -(Course au Lac Oneida - no copy found.) (Published by Beaumont in OC. V. 161-171, Original at Tocqueville)
      -"Quinze jours dans le desert" (List of corrections required in Beaumont published version made by Bonnel from Tocqueville Tocqueville MSS; entire document not copied, just corrections listed.)
      -"Quelques idees sur les raisons qui s'opposent a ce que les Francais aient de bonnes colonies" (Bonnel copy of manuscript in Beaumont's hand. Finally not used in T. and B. in Am.)
      -"24 Hours in New Orleans" and "Suite" (Translation by White from Redier MSS; see White Cat. 3W: Dossier I. 1-2)
    - b. Beaumont Sketchbook: Album of 37 sketches, authentic. (Box 11)
      Album found by GWP at Beaumont-la-Chartre and presented to GWP by Mme de Larminat.
      -also package of cliches and proofs (see separate box)
      - Glass plate negatives of Beaumont Sketchbook (B.III.b) (Box 12)
    - c. Photos of Second Beaumont Sketchbook: (Box 14)
      Romanet Album (dubious, perhaps copies by Gustave de Beaumont's brothers?) This album was found with Vicomte de Romanet, Chateau de Guillets, par Courgeoust, Orne. [On further consideration, I believe this authentic Beaumont sketchbook, with some original sketches and some elaborate, second-stage sketches in ink--GWP, 1964]
      -list of 31 by GWP.
      -29 cliches and proofs - positives (see separate box.)
      -9 discarded cuts: not used in book (see separate box)
      - Glass plate negatives of Second Beaumont Sketchbook (B.III.c) (Box 12)
      - 9 discarded cuts: not used in book (Box 13)
    - d. 22 line tracings by GWP from Beaumont Album and Tocqueville Tocqueville manuscripts (see end papers of T. and B. in Am.) (Box 14)
      This package includes list of Beaumont Album sketches not reproduced or photographed in any form.
  - Tocqueville - Beaumont Correspondence, 1830-1831; 4 (Box 16)
    For these letters, see below C.I.a.2.
    -8 mai, 1830, Versailles, Tocqueville to Beaumont (Original from Larminat)
    -16 mai, 1830, Paris, Tocqueville to Beaumont (Original from Larminat)
    -11-14 mars, 1831, Tocqueville to Beaumont (Original from Larminat)
  - Miscellaneous materials about American Trip and American contacts found by G. W. Pierson in U.S., 5
    - a. Photostats of Francis Lieber correspondence (Box 15)
      -16 9bre, 1832, Paris, Beaumont to Francis Lieber, 4 sheets (From Hunt: Robson: Not to be used without permission of that library)
      -10 July 1839, Paris, Tocqueville to Francis Lieber, 2 sheets (From Hunt: Robson: Not to be used without permission of that library)
      -24 Nov. 1839, Columbia, Francis Lieber to Tocqueville, fair copy, 2 sheets (From Hunt: Robson: Not to be used without permission of that library)
      -16 aout, 1841, La Grange, Beaumont to Francis Lieber, 2 sheets (From Hunt: Robson: Not to be used without permission of that library)
      -14 aout, 1842, Paris, Tocqueville to Francis Lieber, 2 sheets (From Hunt: Robson: Not to be used without permission of that library)
      -22 April, 1844, Paris, Tocqueville to Francis Lieber, 2 sheets (From Hunt: Robson: Not to be used without permission of that library)
      -22 May, 1844, Paris, Beaumont to Francis Lieber, 2 sheets (From Hunt: Robson: Not to be used without permission of that library)
      -31 May 1844, Paris, Beaumont to Francis Lieber, 2 sheets (From Hunt: Robson: Not to be used without permission of that library)
      -18 7bre 1844, Tocqueville, Tocqueville to Francis Lieber, 3 sheets (From Hunt: Robson: Not to be used without permission of that library)
      -13 9bre 1844, Paris, Tocqueville to Francis Lieber, 4 sheets (From Hunt: Robson: Not to be used without permission of that library)
      -2 Dec. 1844, Paris, Mme de Tocqueville and Tocqueville to Francis Lieber, 2 sheets (From Hunt: Robson: Not to be used without permission of that library)
      -8 jan. 1845, Paris, Mme de Tocqueville and Tocqueville to Francis Lieber, 2 sheets (From Hunt: Robson: Not to be used without permission of that library)
      -18 May, 1845, Paris, Tocqueville and Mme de Tocqueville to Francis Lieber, 2 sheets (From Hunt: Robson: Not to be used without permission of that library)
      -1 July 1845, Paris, Tocqueville to Francis Lieber, 2 sheets (From Hunt: Robson: Not to be used without permission of that library)